front to back with ferment, with mix,
from scratch. This took me an hour. San
ti mu dou, you have no excuse not to try
it. Da ga hu, we're making Shanghai
Shanghainese. We're making river land
food today. We're making little river
land hot pockets. These are called sheng
jian bao, or as you would say where
they're from, san ti mu dou, which
directly translates into raw seared
not fried, seared. Jian, we're talking
mantou. Sheng jian mantou. The idea is
it's a lightly fermented dough. Uh
usually a mantou dough stuffed with xian
rou, or fresh meat, which is a
flavoring, not a description, of ground
pork laced with ginger, scallion, salt,
sugar, sesame oil, sometimes chicken
stock, and that's pretty much it. Xian
rou, or fresh meat, is a very lightly
flavored filling. And this is a street
side snack that originated in the late
Qing Dynasty to early 20th century. That
was when it became popular as a street
food. Today, we're going to experiment
with minimal [__] maximum cooking.
Uh over here I have fillings. On this
board are some ginger, probably in the
neighborhood of 20 g, a [__] ton of
scallions, or green onions, or spring
onions, depending on where you're from,
in the neighborhood of 200 g, which is
also known as the wrong amount of green
onions. It's too much, but I like mine
heavily seasoned and green. It's how I
like to sneak my vegetables in. And half
a kilo, or 500 g, of ground pork in the
lean fat ratio of 2 to 8. With xian rou,
you don't want too much fat, or it won't
taste like meat, it'll taste like a
sludge. That is the filling. Seasonings
aside, I also have this, which is a cup
of fresh chicken broth, which is not
true. Uh it's actually a stock pot that
I dissolved with hot water. And I'm
going to be using this to moisten the
meat.
That was not pleasant.
Reminds me of Bovril. In the magical
land of the UK, and northerners have a
very specific culture. So, if you're
from the north, you might go to a game
of football, and to drink a hot cup of
thick brown soup. It's literally a cup
of gravy. Sorry, it's gravy that you
have while watching the football game.
It's a very, very manly drink for older
gentlemen who go down the pub more often
than they should. Down the pub, and they
pretend like they're not racist. How can
I be racist if I cheer for that black
fellow when he scored that goal? And
mhm mhm mhm.
No, then the Jon Snow accent. I don't
know if this is true, but the Jon Snow
accent essentially I want to say it's
like a Yorkshire accent, but I think
everybody only had that accent because
Sean Bean can't do any other accents.
Everybody else had to be
his accent to make the story go forward.
Cuz like technically in that time, if
you were a lord, you would have a light
accent. I promised less [__] and
now I'm talking about Game of Thrones.
Anyways, so
in here is some flour.
I mixed low protein and high protein or
cake and bread to create all-purpose
flour. If you live in a country with
all-purpose flour, just use that. If
you're in Asia, use dumpling flour. If
you're in France, well, if you're in
France, you wouldn't be making this. You
would be trying to make a baguette.
You'd be Anyways, so half a kilo of
flour in there and yeast. The recipe
should be 1% of yeast by volume in
baker's percentage. So if I'm using half
a kilo of flour, I should put in 5 g of
yeast. But I want to eat this quite
soon, and unlike in Western fermented
foods where ideally you have a nice long
time to ferment, and what you're indeed
eating is the yeastiness of the food. In
a lot of fermented Asian doughs, what we
want is the flouriness
of the dough. Mian Xiang Wei. This is
also why when before we used to leaven
our steam buns naturally, you would
actually put alkali ingredients inside
to get rid of the sourness. So in this
regard, feel free to use a lot of yeast.
Makes it faster, makes it more sweet to
the nose, and it doesn't give time for
those beery flavors to develop, which in
this context is actually good. So,
there's no right or wrong to it. It's
just that East and West, we treat fuel
differently, we treat ingredients
differently, and most importantly, we
hold different things near and dear.
This is salt. I only put in some for
funsies. You don't have to. In fact, you
probably shouldn't with a dough like
this. I just do it as a knee-jerk
reaction. And here is some sugar, 5% by
weight of flour, just to accentuate the
grain flavor, because sweet on the
tongue does help you identify more with
the fragrance of white refined flour.
And in here goes 55% hydration water.
So, 55 * 5, go.
275. Good. Good. If you live in a very
humid place, feel free to bring that
down to 250, i.e., 50% hydration.
And this is indeed the same dough that
you would use for mantou, baozi, but
we've already talked about this in
previous episodes. If you're going to
knead any dough by hand, this is one
that I highly recommend, cuz it's easy,
and you don't actually need to put a lot
of development on it. As long as it's
not dry, give it 2-3 minutes, it comes
together as dough, it can be lumpy, rest
it for 20 minutes as it ferments, and
you have a nice dough. Cuz remember,
we're not in San Francisco. This is not
Tartine. You're not trying to make a
like a custardy chewy laochabing. You
want it to just be squishy, bouncy,
juji. It's a cute texture. This is good
enough for dough.
If you don't have one of these, feel
free to use a stand mixer or a food
processor at home. Food processors make
really good doughs. They also create a
lot of heat, so instead of using warm
water for this dough, I can just let it
run in the machine for a minute longer,
and it'll be warm and help me ferment.
Cool. See?
This is as doughy as it needs to be.
Don't even bother making it too smooth
cuz as it ferments it's going to create
a little bit more elasticity and
plasticity in the dough. And also we're
going to break it down into small balls
and then squish it into an annoying
shape. So who gives a [__] if your dough
is smooth at this point? Let it hang out
on the counter. So this is my stand
mixer bowl. Feel free to do this with
your hands and I'm going to throw
everything in the bowl. Now at this
point I want What do I want? Answer.
>> White pepper.
>> Yes, yes. The why do I want white
pepper?
>> Uh because it's for the lamb.
>> Because we Shanghai knees. And some
white pepper. Feel free to omit this if
you don't like the flavor of white
pepper. And a little bit of sugar. Why
sugar?
>> To season.
>> No.
>> No?
>> Why sugar?
>> Because it's Shanghai food.
>> There we go. That is This is This is
>> [laughter]
>> This is the correct time to say some
[__] like that. So put what anybody else
in the country would consider too much
sugar inside your meat. Maybe in the
neighborhood of 10 g. Also feel free to
omit if that doesn't suit your fancy.
You should season this with soy sauce.
But because she knew it's supposed to
look blonde and white and you want the
soup to be golden. I like to use white
soy sauce. When I use white soy sauce it
gives me the cleanest [music] flavor. Uh
not that heavy on the ferment. Generally
speaking the darker the soy sauce the
more fermenty it tastes. Besides
Kikkoman which just tastes like [__]
It's like the most popular soy sauce in
North America. It's like you You know
the little plastic fish?
>> Oh yeah, yeah.
>> Yeah. Kikkoman.
Because
if you didn't put it in a plastic fish
they wouldn't know what it's used for.
I guess. I don't I don't know why. I
don't know why it's a plastic fish. So I
like to put in white soy sauce to
maintain the color and then a little bit
of sesame oil to redo the seasoning. And
from here I throw it on my stand mixer
and let her rip.
I'm going to put in a little bit
of gelatin powder. And the reason I put
in gelatin powder is like our previous
soup dumpling episode where I want to
cheat a sticky broth. Now, instead of
making a pita, which is a gelatinized
pork skin broth, and then cooling it
down and chopping it up and folding it
in, I'm going to throw in stockpot water
and then bind it with dry gelatin and
let the gelatin hydrate through my
installed stockpot water, thus achieving
pretty much the same effect. Beat the
living [__] out of your food and
emulsify it in. So, this is the effect
you want. See the stringiness?
You want the meat fibers to look like
that. So, yeah, that. That's the texture
we want. Kind of stringy.
That is something I don't recommend you
do
to taste your seasoning, but that is
what every laoshi fu I've ever met has
done is just finger your raw meat and
then stick it in your mouth. This is
also what brings me to the point of
telling you that if any traditional
Chinese chef tries to tell you anything
about cleanliness or food safety, just
ignore it.
Because a lot of Chinese chefs will be
like, "That's not clean. That's not
safe. Western food is gross. Everyone's
fingering their food and tasting it."
But they also do that with raw pork and
hang chickens at room temperature in the
middle of the Hong Kong ghetto for 6
hours. So, don't don't take what we say
seriously. Remember, and I think I speak
for most Asians when I say this, what we
like is being smart, but what we like
even more than that is bit. We love to
bit.
If you take away me running my [__]
mouth,
this is like a 20-minute process. The
dough takes 5 minutes, the filling takes
10 with the chopping included, and
you're good to go. So, this can go in
the fridge and hang out for a little bit
while you clean up your counter and this
proofs. The entire process should take
no more than half an hour. Remember how
big the dough was before? See how it's
already growing? That's because I put in
a lot of yeast. And this doesn't have to
double in size. A gentle fermentation is
all you need because you want the
texture to be quite
tight.
So, yeah. Let it rest in the fridge for
half an hour. I'm going to clean up. See
you guys in just a sec.
Welcome back, guys. I said half an hour,
but it's been like 5 minutes. So, now
what we're going to do
is weigh our dough out. 820 g means if
you are a lazy [__] you can divide that
into 10 balls of dough equally, and that
will give you burger-sized shengjian
mantou. You want them to be about golf
ball-sized. If you're psychotic or have
issues, you can make them even smaller
still. And then they would be called the
mooji mantou thumb shengjian bao, which
is like a trendy thing that happened
kind of recently. All right, so this is
my least favorite part of this process,
and you don't have to do it. I'm just
doing it cuz I want a consistent
outcome. To be honest, this is our
second time filming this cuz the first
time one of my colleagues labeled gum
arabic as gelatin, which is why it came
out all jizzy and disgusting. It
literally looked like slime. Um and I
want to make sure they're perfect this
time.
>> What's the difference?
>> Between gum arabic and gelatin? Well,
one is Muslim and the other one
>> Is it edible?
>> Muslims?
>> No, no. I mean
>> Yeah, gum arabic is of course.
Yeah, absolutely. It's in uh it's in
annoying ice cream. Yeah, where they
have it, don't have it. Have it, don't
have it. Have it, don't have it.
Give me your money.
>> [laughter]
>> Welcome to Istanbul, [__]
So, generally speaking with shengjian,
there's two categories: thick-skinded
and thin-skinded. The thin-skinded
xiaoyang is a recent development. And by
recent, I mean like within 100 years. Uh
and it's not very street foody. The
other one is thick-skinded, so it's more
dough forward with a little bit of meat
to flavor the dough inside, which is
more poor people like original style.
How thick or thin the skin is it depends
entirely on your patience.
Should? I mean, there's a lot of us in
North America, so wherever us are, I
guess there's going to be these. Take a
ball, flatten it out with an empty palm.
Not like this, like this. You want the
edges to be flatter than the inside, a
mound, if you will. Now, there's going
to be a sticky side and a non-sticky
side. The non-sticky side faces down.
You hold your off hand underneath it
with three fingers like this and your
thumb on top of your off hand. With your
dominant hand, you roll the rolling pin
up to the middle finger of your off hand
that's underneath the dough, then back
the [__] off, thus creating a mound in
the middle with thin edges. Thusly, when
you go to fill and seal, the gathering
of doughs at the top will create an even
thickness all the way around. Now, if
you don't have the hand dexterity, seal
it on the counter
like I am doing. All you're doing is
sending the dough from one hand into the
other and you're done.
It is e mo i yang. It's just fermented
shao mai. One's steamed and one's fried,
but roughly they're the exact same food.
I have drafted the help of our dough
food expert, the Queen Mum.
Her Majesty the Queen Mother, yes. And
she has learned through years of working
at Magpie to have a pixelated face. Oh,
this episode we also have a new
colleague. This is his first day filming
with us. Do you have an English name?
You have an English name?
Shen. Shen and Shen.
Oh, that's a great question. Thank you
for asking. So, when I do dough foods
like this, I always work with a pure
starch. By pure starch, I mean corn
starch, rice flour, potato starch,
tapioca starch, because it hydrates very
poorly. It doesn't soak up water very
well, so it can stay powdery for long
and I can use less of it. If you use
flour, it'll hydrate, and then you're
just creating a dough outside of your
dough. This is also why when you look at
a lot of modern bakeries, like those big
loaves of sourdough,
you know how the top, the dust, the
flour is always snowy white, even though
the bread is black?
That's starch. That's not flour. Flour
would go brown. So, now we are going to
do the actual cooking.
Generally speaking, I prefer to cook
these with the wrinkled side down. That
is the traditional way to cook these. If
you look at pictures of them on the
internet, it's always the wrinkly side
down. However, that does mean there's a
higher chance of this exploding and
your entire pot of food up. If you want
it to be safer, cook on the flat side of
dough, so that when steam and pressure
build up and there's a blowout, it's
just juice on top, and it won't ruin the
food in your pan. But, if you want it to
be traditional, you want seam side down.
Look at that. Beautiful. Look. Look at
that [__] Wow. Beautiful.
All right. Cool. So, start in a cold pan
and bring the heat into it. Now, you
definitely want there to be room in
between, but what they usually do is
>> [music]
>> they put a lot of fat in the pan until
it comes up pretty much a third of the
way up the dough. You can throw the fat
away later, but I always recommend you
start with a lot of fat. Remember, this
is a shallow fry, yeah? Make sure that
all the kids in the pool are moving
around.
Everybody feels safe and warm. Now, you
want it to be on a medium-low heat, at
which point you slap a lid on. Cool.
Now, you always want the noise to be
If you can hear that noise,
there we go.
Okay. Everybody shut the [__] up.
[__]
Yeah. That noise. No.
That noise right there, you want it to
you want the sound to be
like it like the the pan's gossiping at
you. You don't want it to be pissed off,
you don't want it to be screaming, you
just want gossiping. So, give that about
3 minutes and we'll check on it. So,
this
This is the noise that we're looking
for.
Now, here's the thing that I must tell
you guys about this kind of food. If
you're afraid that the dough, like this,
is not cooked because it is steamed food
at this point at the top,
that's fine. That's perfectly
understandable.
Just add more water cuz you're very
unlikely to overcook this. So, if that's
the case, then I'd much rather you err
on the side of caution and give it some
extra steam if you feel it necessary.
Now, over here, I'm going to put a
little bit of garnish.
Now, what I like to do is I just flip it
over.
Flip it over. Here we go. This is how
you would serve them. So, while they're
hot, throw on some scallions
and a little bit of sesame and you have
a full-ass meal. There you go.
All right. [__] yeah. Cool. We're in the
final stretch, guys. How could you
possibly eat something so fatty and rich
without vinegar? There we go.
If there is no other ingredient that you
put in your pantry, [music] this is one
that you should. All right, let's do it.
Hell yeah, brother.
Now, if you want these to be a little
bit taller, you would make a slightly
drier dough.
I prefer this cuz the flatter they are,
the bigger the crispy [music] section
is. Listen to that.
That's the sound you want to hear.
Let me put it this way. If you're Asian,
you'll understand what I'm saying.
There are burger places in China.
And they pretty much all fail.
Because why would you pay 10 times the
amount of money
for a 10th of the flavor when you have
this [music] in your backyard?
Right? This would have cost maybe like
what?
60 kuai for all of this, which is less
than 10 American dollars for all this
food. And that's enough for three
people. It's tender, it's juicy,
it's full of protein if that matters to
you.
I'm just making sure that everybody has
enough to eat. All right, let's wrap
this video up so we can have staff meal.
Let's [snorts] recap, guys. The dough is
all-purpose flour or half bread flour,
half cake flour with 50 to 55%
hydration. 1 to 4% of yeast depending on
how fast you want it, so that's anywhere
between 5 to 20 g of yeast. I used 25 g
of sugar, can omit, trust me it won't be
sweet. Tiny pinch of salt.
Whip it in your mixer for 2 minutes and
let it hang out on the counter for 20
minutes. Doesn't have to be full
development, just a ball of dough is
fine. The filling was half a kilo of
pork, 200 g of scallions, 20 g of
ginger, one stock pot mixed in with
about 150 g of water, roughly 10 g of
gelatin powder mixed up with the
seasonings, white soy sauce, use normal
soy if you don't have it, white pepper
and sesame oil with a pinch of sugar.
After everything is mixed, throw it in
the fridge, let it hang out for a bit,
and then knock your dough down into
parts while your meat's chilling down.
Fill it up, smash it together, fry it
shallow in a layer of fat until one
side's crispy, spoonful of water goes
in, cap goes on, and you're done. Front
to back with ferment, with mix, from
scratch, [snorts] this took me an hour.
With the [__] coming out of my
mouth, took like
two.
Easy food. You have no excuse not to try
it. This has been a minimum [__]
maximum food episode. Let me know if
this is the kind of content you prefer
as opposed to me running my mouth about
fake history. Talk often, talk soon,
take care, guys.